[instrumental music]
[bell ringing]
High school, huh? Must bring
back some memories for you.
Friday nights,
your friends from band
strapping on
those funny hats.
You know what?
I am not gonna take the bait.
And then after practice,
a little spin the bottle..
in some wood paneled
rec room.
Whatever you say.
Rigsby,
what have we got?
JackMcTierney, 28.
English teacher.
ME, puts the time of death
between 6 o'clock
and 9 o'clock last night.
Apparently he likes to
stay late and go jogging
around the campus.
Cho's searching
his locker now.
[sighs]
Looks like it's a blunt-force
trauma to the head.
'We have a murder weapon?'
No, but the ME thinks
it was metal.
When we got here, there were
bats in the equipment bins.
We're testing them
for blood now.
Did we contact the family?
Yeah, but they're all
back East.
He's single,
lives alone.
Alright, start setting
up interviews
'anybody who was here between
6:00 and 9:00 last night.'
You got it.
Look at that bruising
around the eye.
Mm. It's faded. Looks like
it's about a week old.
Be good to know
how that happened.
Well, let's ask
the principal.
That guy?
Cheap power suit, phone holster,
Bluetooth, large watch.
Has petty tyrant
written all over him.
Excuse me! Sir?
Hi. I'm Agent Lisbon.
This is Patrick Jane.
We're with the CBI.
Principal Carl Snyder.
Thank you so much
for coming so quickly.
Uh, did Mr. McTierney
have any problems?
Trouble with a student?
No, I don't think so.
He was a great teacher.
He started working here
right after college.
Uh, bright kid.
Could have made money
doing so many things,
but he loved teaching.
We were lucky to have him.
Now I have a
grief counseling session
- starting momentarily--
- Excellent. We'll come.
Uh, how did he get
the black eye?
He said that he,
was playing basketball
with some students
after school.
But you didn't believe him?
Well, why would he lie?
Of course I believed him.
No, you didn't.
Well, why would Ilie?
Probably just
bureaucratic instinct.
Now if you suspected
that the black eye story
was false, did you have
any notion of the true story?
- No.
- Hmm?
Like I said, he was very
popular among everyone
students and faculty alike.
Not everyone. I went
through McTierney's locker.
Nothing unusual. But I found
this in his briefcase.
[instrumental music]
Oh. This is
very interesting.
I had the honor of working
with Jack McTierney
for the past five years.
He was a good teacher.
And he will be missed.
Thank you, Mr. Loveland.
Now is there anyone else who
would like to say something
about Mr. McTierney?
We-well, I'd-I'd
like to say something.
Mr. Jane, this is a very
sensitive moment.
Yeah, they're just teenagers.
They'll get over it.
[Patrick clears throat]
Good morning, everyone.
I'm Patrick Jane.
I'm with the CBI.
I'm sorry for
everyone's loss. Uh..
I know you were close
to Mr. McTierney
and I was hoping
that one of you could tell me
who wrote this letter
that we found.
[rustling]
"Dear Mr. McT..
[sighs]
'"I saw what you did,
and I'm disgusted.'
'"You are a total pig."
Exclamation point.'
"I used to think
you were special
"but you're just a hypocrite
like the rest of them.
"I can't believe I ever
thought you were cool.
'"I hate you."'
[murmuring]
'Who would write
such a letter? Hmm?'
Clearly someone
who felt betrayed.
A sensitive soul who now
feels deep remorse
for having spoken so harshly.
Someone seated right here
in this room.
Yes.
[murmuring]
You.
While everyone else
was looking around
trying to figure out
who wrote the letter
'you weren't.'
You knew who wrote
the letter
because it was you.
Isn't that right?
I'm sorry.
Oh, Lisbon, you're on.
[murmuring]
Wow.
Hey! Hey, stop!
Drama, huh?
Anyone else have
anything to say?
[theme music]
Why'd you write
this letter, Rachel?
[sniffling]
Mr. McT was my favorite teacher.
He always talked about
self-respect.
'He wanted us girls to
value ourselves for our minds.'
I-I mean, he was cool
with us.
He didn't treat us
like idiot kids.
Well, what changed?
Three nights ago,
I was driving
to the food bank
where I volunteer.
It's in kind of
a sketchy neighborhood.
And I saw Mr. McTierney
talking to, like, a hooker.
And they were fighting.
Well, arguing.
'And then she got
into his car.'
I mean..
He's a teacher.
What did she look like?
Here. I took a picture.
[sniffles]
[phone ringing]
Text me that picture
and the address that you
saw her. Excuse me.
Cho, what's up?
[Kimball]
'Forensics finished up.'
None of the school's bats
show traces of blood.
And we found a baggie
of homemade pills
in McTierney's car.
Looks like MDMA. Ecstasy.
[Teresa]
'Turns out our victim
had a few secrets.'
I've got a student here
who says she saw him
in an argument
with a prostitute.
I'll forward you a picture
of the hooker and the address.
'You and Rigsby see
if you can track her down.'
Got it.
[beeping]
Jane?
Hey.
Hmm? Ecstasy.
Interesting.
[door opens]
No, you go on.
I'm gonna stay here.
bye.
I'm sorry. May I help you?
No. No help necessary.
Uh, you are?
Ms. Austin.
Uh, drama teacher.
Ah, I was just admiring
your set.
Uh, what play are you doing?
"Hamlet."
A modern interpretation,
as you can see.
"To die, to sleep.
"To sleep,
perchance to dream.
"Ay, there's the rub."
That's right.
I'm, uh, worried
about Rachel.
She's in the play.
She's really a good kid.
Oh, she'll be fine
unless she murdered
Mr. McT.
- What do you think?
- No.
No. Uh.. I can't imagine.
Hmm.
[laughing]
[chuckles]
Well, if you'll excuse me,
I have five minutes
to get bad coffee
from the teachers' lounge.
Mmm. Enjoy.
[whooshing]
[grunting]
[instrumental music]
[whooshing]
[tapping]
En garde.
Well, it's no fun
if you just give up.
Are you one of the cops?
Cop-adjacent, maybe.
- Are you in the play?
- Yeah, I am.
I'm Jeremiah.
I play the ghost.
"I am thy father's spirit
"doomed for a certain term
to walk the night."
Sounds cool when you say it.
I'm not sure
I'm pulling it off.
I only auditioned
to meet the girls.
How's that going for you?
Not good.
[sighs]
Well, Jeremiah, you seem
like a fellow in the know.
Let me ask you this.
Where could I buy
some drugs around here?
- What?
- Ecstasy, preferably.
I have no idea.
Wh-why would you ask?
Uh, I want to meet
the bad kids.
You know, the kind that might
sell drugs to a teacher.
Every school has them.
Where do they hang out?
Um, I wo.. I wouldn't know
where they hang out.
Mm, the bad kids
keep real low profile.
Principal Snyder's
kind of a hard-ass.
Hmm. You wouldn't know, huh?
Do you swear?
Yeah. I swear.
Well fought.
Off with you.
I know the due date's
just an estimate.
But it.. I mean, it could be
today, right?
Yea.. Just promise me that
you'll call or text.
Sorry. Sarah's freaking out.
- How are you doing?
- Yeah, good. Solid.
Definitely not about
to have a heart attack.
Hey.
Hey, now, back it up.
I'm just waiting on my laundry.
Laundry? In that outfit?
What are you,
a fashion critic?
We're looking for this girl.
'You seen her?'
I don't know.
I lost my glasses.
Maybe if I had some money
for a new pair.
Now I see.
That's like White Chenille.
Usually works
over on Fremont.
Thank you.
But she won't be out yet.
You know where she stays?
Come on, honey.
We've been over this.
[indistinct chatter]
Hmm.
[door opens]
Nice bathroom, Luis.
Uh, very clean.
Sorry?
I was just saying, bathroom
it's, uh, spotless.
Where are all the bad kids?
Bad kids? I-I don't know.
Okay. Yeah.
Nice chatting with you.
[dramatic music]
[rattling]
Hello?
Uh, wait!
[slamming]
Hello, Mr. Jane.
I'm sorry, if I'd have known
you wanted to come down here
I would have had Luis
escort you.
Perhaps you can help me out.
I'm trying to find
the delinquents.
Well, I..
Found one myself,
or at least his shoes
but he managed to get away.
I don't think they're
gonna help you much.
Mr. McTierney taught
mostly advanced classes.
Yes, but it's the bad apples
that have the real dirt.
And where are they?
During class,
the kids are in class.
It's a revolutionary
concept, I know.
[bell ringing]
Well.
If you'll excuse me,
that's lunch.
Speaking of which,
I'm a little peckish.
Where's the cafeteria?
[sighs]
- Yes?
- Are you Chenille?
No. Who's Chenille?
I'm Rigsby. This is Cho.
We're with CBI.
Look, we know you go
by Chenille
and your real name's
Lindy Hayes.
Seems like you got it all
figured out.
What do you need me for?
You were with this man,
Jack McTierney
three nights ago?
Yeah, so what?
I see him a lot.
So he was a regular
of yours?
No. He was
my English teacher.
What is this about?
[indistinct chattering]
Hey. Excuse me.
Can I borrow this?
Oh, dear.
You can have that back.
[all gasps]
Excuse me. I just need
a moment of your time
then you can get back
to your lunch.
I'd like you all
to raise your hands.
All of you.
It's official police business.
Raise them high.
Put your hand down
if you're on the Dean's list.
[indistinct chatter]
[Patrick]
'Good.'
Okay, good.
'Now put your hand down
if you're taking the SATs'
or planning to take
the SATs.
Okay then.
Put your hand down if you've
never smoked a cigar..
'Never mind.'
Carry on.
Enjoy your meat loaf.
[indistinct chatter]
[birds chirping]
[groaning]
[male #1]
'Here get him.'
[indistinct chattering]
[grunting]
[rustling]
[male #2]
What was that?
Ahh!
Bad kids, at last!
Uhh! No need to run.
Don't even think about it.
The place is surrounded.
Snipers on the rooftops.
Just kidding. Who's running
the show here, you?
Or..
You.
What do you want?
I'm Patrick.
What's your name?
- Krista.
- Krista. I come in peace.
So which of you crazy cats
is gonna help me
solve McTierney's murder, huh?
[Patrick]
Wow.
[indistinct chattering]
You really are bad.
What do you wanna know?
Well, while the rest of the kids
are stuck inside
sharpening their pencils,
you're out here roaming free.
I bet you know way more about
what's really going on, right?
Like who's selling
the ecstasy, for starters.
I wish I knew someone.
That would..
That would definitely
be a popular kid.
What about McTierney?
Did he have any secret vices?
No. He was a square.
Super clean-cut.
Which is why it's so weird
he was tight with Loveland
'cause Loveland's
a crazy drunk.
Loveland?
The career counselor?
- Yeah.
- Hmm.
See, a while back, um
Loveland confiscated
my friend's cell phone.
Mm-hmm.
So my friend broke
into his office
and found like a million
of those little
vodka airplane bottles,
empty.
Well, thanks, Krista.
Very much.
You know, when you wake up
tomorrow morning
and you look in the mirror,
you will see yourself
as if for the very first time,
and you will decide
'to never smoke
cigarettes again.'
[instrumental music]
Thank..
Thank you.
How did you know
Jack McTierney?
He was my teacher.
Like three years ago.
Before I dropped out
of school.
Back then,
he tried to help me
with this problem I was having
with my stepfather.
What was the problem?
Take a wild guess.
If your stepfather
was abusing you
you can still have him
prosecuted.
Whatever.
I ran away to the city.
Problem solved.
But I guess Mr. McTierney
felt guilty, or something.
'Cause ever since then,
he's been trying to rescue me.
He freaked when I told him
I was turning tricks.
What did he say?
You know, that I could still
have a normal life.
Stuff like that.
Then afterward, he'd come
to see me like once a week
buy me a cup of coffee
talk to me about getting
my GED.
But I didn't want to hear it.
So we fought.
We found drugs on McTierney.
Ecstasy.
Couldn't have been
his stuff.
He was a total
straight arrow.
Was it yours?
Ecstasy?
That's for amateurs.
Do you know if he was having
any problems at school?
I don't know.
I mean, he had a couple
other projects like me.
I guess one of them
could have gone wrong.
Projects?
You know, kids he was
trying to help.
You got any names?
He tried to keep that stuff
pretty private.
But I heard him, arguing
on the phone with someone.
'Martin.'
Thanks.
You've been very helpful.
L-let me know if I can
do anything else.
I want to help..
For Mr. McTierney.
If you want to help,
you should do what he wanted.
Go back to school.
[indistinct chattering]
[bell ringing]
Mr. Loveland.
You got a minute?
Of course. Come in.
Yeah. A-anything
I can do to help.
Well, in that case, why did you
punch Mr. McTierney?
How did you know that?
Oh. Well, I-I didn't,
but you just told me.
Also, drunk people
aren't really known
for their impulse control.
Hey. Perfectly
understandable.
You're working with
overachieving children all day.
Who wouldn't want
to take the edge off? Huh?
Look. I know what you
must be thinking
but I had eight years sober.
And, my wife left me
and w-we got a new principal,
and, well, I started thinking
that a drink might
be a good idea.
About a month ago,
I, uh...tested that theory.
Mmm. How'd that go?
Okay. For a while.
Then I started drinking
before work
and I realized that
I was out of control.
You confided in McTierney.
I thought I could trust him.
I was wrong.
He told the principal.
Yeah.
He screwed me royally.
Doesn't seem like something
McTierney would do.
I know. But when I asked Snyder
for some time off
he knew about the drinking.
He couldn't fire me for it,
but he could make my life hell.
Okay.
[Patrick clears throat]
Uh, wh-wh-where were you
when you, uh, uh, told
McTierney you relapsed?
W-we were in the men's room.
Was there anyone else there?
You think I'd be talking
about that kind of stuff
if there were?
No, of course not.
Thank you.
[bell ringing]
- I take it no baby yet.
- 'No.'
Got anything
to distract me?
Well, we finally got into
McTierney's computer
and looked at his calendar.
He had an advisory meeting
scheduled with a kid
named Martin Klubock
the night he died.
- Really?
- Yeah, but it's weird.
Martin's an 'A' student,
and he has no history
of disciplinary action
at school.
So why was he one of
Mr. McTierney's projects?
Well..
[sighs]
I looked into
his attendance records.
He's been out sick
a bunch of times this year.
And there was a trip
to the emergency room.
A broken rib
and some stitches.
You think it's
some kind of abuse?
Could be, although his folks
don't have a record.
Anyway, he called in sick
to school today.
Yeah. Cho and I will
check it out. Gladly.
That guilty creatures
sitting in a play
have, by the, the
cunning of the scene
so struck to the soul
that presently..
They have proclaimed
their malefactions
their shortcomings.
Mind if I borrow
some of this? Thank you.
For murder,
though it have no tongue
will speak with most,
magnificent organ.
I'll have these players
play something
like the murder of my father
before mine uncle.
'If he but blench..'
I-I know my course.
- Line?
- Billy!
We have been
over this.
You should have been
off book a week ago.
The spirit that
I have seen may be a devil
and the devil hath power
to assume a pleasing shape
and so on and so forth.
The play's the thing
wherein I'll catch
the conscience of the king.
[Ms. Austin]
'That was amazing!'
Are you an actor, Mr. Jane?
Well, I've, done a little
stage work here and there.
Wow!
I hope you guys
were paying attention.
Billy, did you hear
the passion
and clarity of his delivery,
the, the rhythm?
Yeah. I heard.
Okay. Everybody take five
while I try to find out
what happened with the programs.
Well, maybe Mr. Jane
could give us a few tips.
I'm sure Mr. Jane doesn't
want to be bothered
with our little play.
- Oh, it's no bother.
- 'Well, then..'
A brilliant idea.
It's not every day we get
a visit from a professional.
In that case, let's warm up with
a simple enunciation exercise
shall we?
Toy boat, ten times, fast.
- 'Toy boat.'
- Toy boat. Toy boat.
[in unison]
Toy boat. Toy boat. Toy boat.
- Toy boat. Toy boat.
- 'Faster.'
Jeremiah, you're not
projecting.
Inhale from the bottom
of your stomach
not from the top
of your throat.
Deep breaths.
Ay, that incestuous,
that adulterate beast--
More voice, more voice.
Ay, that incestuous,
that adulterate beast!
[Ms. Austin]
'Yes!'
Yes, bravo, Jeremiah!
You are good, Mr. Jane.
Any notes for Billy,
our Hamlet?
Well, remember, Billy,
never break character
even if you forget
your lines.
I mean, the audience
will never know
as long as you keep going.
Thank you. I have been
telling him that.
And Hamlet's not as pleased
with himself as you are
so, uh, dial that back
a touch.
As for you, Ms. Austin
you have, uh..
something on your...coat.
'Huh. A leaf.'
There. All set.
Oh. Thank you, Mr. Jane.
You should come back tomorrow
and see the play.
I'm sure all the kinks
will be worked out by then.
Yeah. Break a leg.
- Martin Klubock?
- Uh, yes.
I'm Agent Rigsby.
This is Agent Cho.
We're with CBI.
Your parents home?
Uh, no.
No, they're at a sales
convention in Tucson.
But they'll be back
Saturday.
We need to talk to you
about Mr. McTierney.
Yeah. Of course.
You got something burning?
Uh, no. No, it's fine.
It's just some soup.
You had a meeting
with Mr. McTierney last night
an hour before he died.
Uh, I was supposed
to meet with him.
Uh, but I canceled.
I'm coming down
with something.
Really, you got something
burning. I should check it out.
- Uh, no, it's fine.
- No, come on! Hey! Hey!
[hissing]
Hey!
What the hell
are you doing?
[bubbling]
Making ecstasy.
[bell ringing]
[instrumental music]
Et voila.
[indistinct chattering]
[woman over PA]
'Patrick Jane, please report'
'to the principal's office
immediately.'
'I repeat, Patrick Jane,
to the principal's office.'
[door opens]
There he is. The principal
will be in shortly.
[sighs]
What did you do?
Nothing.
11 years in catholic school
and I never got sent to
the principal's office once.
Well, that's because you're
a boring goody-two-shoes.
I didn't say I never did
anything bad.
- I just never got caught.
- Ahh. Touche.
[door opens]
[sighs]
[sniffing]
It has come to my attention
'that Mr. Jane here'
performed an act of vandalism
in the second floor
boys restroom.
A vicious, personal attack
on me.
Jane?
It's true.
Sir, on behalf of the CBI,
I apologize.
I appreciate that.
Mr. Jane?
Jane!
I'm sorry for the senseless
act of graffiti.
That's all.
Very well.
I will send a bill to CBI
which will cover the cost
of cleaning
and I would ask
that as we move forward
with this investigation
it is conducted without
Mr. Jane on site.
Are we agreed?
How'd you know it was me
that graffiti'd the bathroom?
A student told me.
Well, that's strange,
'cause it was during class
and there was no one else
in the bathroom
'cause I checked.
Well, somebody saw something,
didn't they?
Mmm.
You saw something
on your unauthorized
security cameras.
What?
He has unauthorized
security cameras
hidden in the bathrooms.
It's a little creepy, huh?
'I don't know where
you are getting'
your information,
but it is simply not true!
Oh! Oh!
[Patrick]
'Hello!'
Pervy perv perv!
Secret cameras?
That is profoundly illegal.
No. Listen..
Listen to me.
These cameras are for
disciplinary purposes only.
Then why didn't you
tell us?
Because, as you say
strictly speaking,
they are not 100% legal.
- Mm-hmm.
- 'Principal Snyder'
if you're withholding evidence
from this investigation
we've got
a serious problem.
'And the PTA
and the ACLU.'
And all those other acronyms
they're gonna have a host
of problems with you, pal.
I wouldn't think
of withholding evidence.
I'm not an idiot.
I looked through the footage
the night of the murder
and I don't think
there is anything there.
Frankly, I don't care
what you think.
'I want all the footage now.'
Alright. I understand.
[breathing heavily]
Agent Lisbon,
could I ask that we
keep this discreet?
No.
Martin..
...you've been
manufacturing ecstasy
a schedule I,
narcotic.
You're 16 years old.
You can be tried
as an adult
or you can be tried
as a minor.
Believe me, you don't want
to be tried as an adult.
You lied about meeting
Mr. McTierney the night he died.
Okay. I met him.
And he confiscated
your pills?
That's why we found
the drugs on him, right?
Yeah. But he didn't know
I was making them. I swear.
I told him
I found the pills
and he believed me.
What about your parents?
They must have known
that there was
a drug lab in their basement.
Uh, they had no idea
about the drugs.
'I told them it was for
my science fair project.'
Okay.
So why were you meeting
Mr. McTierney?
I had been having
some, trouble,and..
'...he was trying to help me.'
Something to do with your,
uh, trip to the emergency room?
Yeah.
Martin..
Are you getting abused
at home?
No. No way.
My parents aren't around
enough to abuse me.
So you're getting bullied
at school?
Not really.
I mean, kids can be morons,
but...it's not that bad.
I went to high school.
They eat kids
like you for breakfast.
That's what Mr. McTierney
was helping you with, right?
Whatever.
He tried,
but what was he gonna do?
'He couldn't be there
24/7.'
And what kind of wuss needs a
teacher to protect him, anyways?
It just made things worse.
So you decided
to become a drug dealer.
[scoffs]
I just wanted to be popular.
I thought if I became
the cool drug guy
then everything
would be different.
I wasn't even
gonna sell the E
just give it away.
I know that's crazy, but..
I would do anything.
You know what?
I got my ass kicked
in high school.
- Yeah, right.
- No, seriously.
I was 5'4"
till my senior year.
Then I grew a foot.
Things change.
That would be so awesome.
[phone vibrating]
Wait a second.
Hey. What's up?
Your.. Your what broke?
Oh! Oh, oh! Uh, yeah, yeah.
Um, I'm on my way.
'Uh, don't move!'
- Hey.
- Everything okay?
- Her water broke.
That's a good thing,
isn't it?
Yeah. It's, uh...it's happening.
Can you tell Lisbon?
- Yeah, I got you covered.
- Thank you.
Good luck.
[crickets chirping]
[Grace sighs]
'We've watched 60 hours
worth of footage.'
I think it's a dead end.
Patience, grasshopper.
I am being patient.
There.
Back that up.
Okay.
Can you.. Can you
grow that?
bigify it?
I can do a digital zoom.
[Patrick]
'Good.'
- 'You know that kid?'
- 'Our Hamlet.'
Well, that's interesting.
That's well, that's
very interesting.
What's interesting?
I just talked to the DA.
They're gonna go easy
on Martin
but they don't want to pursue
Principal Snyder
on the illegal cameras,
no upside.
Well, that's a shame.
Let's get your jacket on.
- We have to go.
- Where are we going?
Back to school.
[instrumental music]
[indistinct chatter]
Excellent. A full house.
Make sure you get a good seat.
You're not coming with me?
Well, I-I just have to make
a quick stop first.
[sighs]
[rattling]
[Ms. Austin]
'Can I have my thespians
stage left, please?'
'Time for our pre-show circle.
Looking good.'
'Wonderful. Wonderful.'
Five minutes.
Oh. Hello, Mr. Jane.
How's it going back here?
Great. Oh, Sarah.
Time to get
to the light board.
'Lexi, please tuck in
that shirt.'
I-I'm sorry, Mr. Jane.
I have to go.
- It is absolute chaos.
- Of course. Of course.
Jeremiah.
How are you feeling?
You look a little green
around the gills.
Uh.. I'm a little nervous.
Well, that's to be expected.
Why don't I give you
a little breathing exercise
just to, to ground you?
Yeah, sure, anything.
Belly to the lips.
Mm, mm, mm.
- Belly to the lips. Mm..
- Mm.
[ululating]
[both ululating]
Okay. Short, quick breaths.
Yeah. More.
short and quick.
Okay.. Faster.
Now big, deep, long..
Lots of oxygen.
Oh.. Oh.
There you go.
Look how calm
you are now.
Yes, yes.
[indistinct chattering]
um, there's someone
sitting there.
Hi.
Oh, my God!
Should we call
an ambulance?
No. No, no.
I think I'm okay.
I-I don't know
what happened.
You hyperventilated.
Silly boy.
I think he'll be fine.
I don't know that he'll be
able to perform tonight..
But you do have
an understudy, don't you?
We have oneunderstudy,
and he's already being used
because Laertes has mono.
- Oh.
- This is just a disaster.
There's no way we can
go on without a ghost.
Oh, we have to.
We've worked so hard.
Can't we replace him?
Jeremiah wasn't even that good.
Billy, don't say that.
Who could we possibly get
to stand in for him?
I don't know.
It's such an important role.
- Stay down. Stay down.
- I know!
Oh, you could do it,
Mr. Jane.
You already know the lines,
don't you?
Well, I-I-I couldn't possibly.
Oh, please!
We're screwed if you don't.
Yeah, come on, dude!
What do you say,
Ms. Austin?
I think, it's a brilliant idea.
Good job, Rachel.
Okay then. Well..
The show must go on.
Thank you. And you can
stay in what you're wearing.
- It's perfect.
- Uh, uh..
[female #1]
'Two minutes!'
Overture and beginners!
Stay down.
[indistinct chattering]
[mouthing]
Have after. To what
issue will this come?
Something is rotten
in the state of Denmark.
[male #3]
'Heaven will direct it.'
[male #4]
'Nay, let's follow him.'
Alright, Mr. Jane,
Billy, scene five.
You are on.
Wither wilt thou lead me?
'Speak. I'll go no further.'
- 'Mark me.'
- 'I will.'
My hour is almost come
when I to sulphurous
and tormenting flames
'must render myself up.'
- 'Alas, poor ghost.'
- 'Pity me not.'
Lend thy serious hearing
to what I shall unfold.
A tale of murder most foul.
The murder of Mr. McTierney!
[audience murmuring]
Uh, uh, su-surely..
th-thou means the murder
of my father, the king.
A murder born of lust
in the woods
next to the baseball field.
N-nay! Thou means
the woods in Denmark! Right?
A murder born of unnatural lust
between woman and boy.
[audience murmuring]
Um.. uh, line?
A murder committed by you
with this baseball bat.
N-no! I-it wasn't me!
- No?
- It was her!
Whoa, whoa!
Lisbon, we have a runner!
Whoa!
Hey.
[grunting]
Whoa.
[chuckles]
Well, thank you.
You've been a lovely audience.
Sorry we had to close..
early
but you get the general idea.
Pretty much everyone dies
poisoning, stabbing.
Yeah, it's all very sad.
The Scandinavians, huh?
Gloomy bunch.
Oh, and by the way, uh
don't do anything naughty
in the bathrooms.
Principal Snyder has
hidden cameras in there.
'Illegal? Yes.'
Immoral? You decide.
[audience jeering]
Goodnight.
We found the bat
in your house.
Ms. Austin is probably
blaming it all on you.
So help yourself out.
Talk to me.
She's 35. You're 16.
That's statutory rape.
So tell me what happened.
[gasps]
It started last semester
in her acting class.
She was, like, passionate
about everything, you know?
- Mm-hmm.
- It was exciting.
And...she told me
I was talented.
And asked me to audition
for the play.
[Billy]
We started hooking up
after rehearsals.
And then Mr. McTierney saw us when he was jogging that night.
He said he was gonna
go to Principal Snyder.
He said she was
gonna go to jail.
She asked me to go
after him and stop him.
She just wanted to talk
to him, she said
to change his mind.
I-I followed him
through the woods
and out onto
the baseball field.
I begged him not to tell.
I didn't want her
to get in trouble.
[grunting]
[dramatic music]
I know what I did
to Mr. McTierney
is unforgivable
and I wish to God
I could undo it
but you have to understand.
What Billy and I have
is special.
It's real.
I'm not some pervert.
I love him,
and he loves me.
Is that wrong?
Yes.
[sighs]
Lindy, hi.
What are you doing here?
I just wanted to say
thank you
For figuring out what happened
to Mr. McTierney.
Ohh...you're welcome.
And also..
I think I want to do
what he said.
You know,
get out of the life.
That's good, Lindy.
I'm happy for you.
[chuckles]
I feel stupid.
I don't know why
I'm telling you.
It's just I don't really have
anyone else to say it to
now that he's gone.
Well, I know
a social worker.
I'll get you her number.
There's all sorts of programs
and shelters.
She can help you.
Thank you.
[sighs]
Sure.
Hey, how did you know
Billy was having an affair
with the teacher?
They both had leaves
on them
from their make-out spot
in the woods.
That's it?
Well, plus I could see
she liked him.
She was meaner to him
than the other kids.
You know, like Lisbon
is to me.
Shut up!
See?
[phone beeps]
Oh, a text from Rigsby.
[phone vibrating]
[phones beeping]
It's a boy. Benjamin.
He's so cute.
Yeah, if Winston Churchill
was cute.
More like Mao Tse-tung.
Yeah. You're right.
Hush. He's gorgeous.
Yeah. He is gorgeous.
[instrumental music]
[theme music]